字幕制作: 呆呆@CMCT
- Is he here yet? - No.
- 他来了吗？- 没有
- You scared him. - I gotta take a massive piss.
- 你一定吓坏他了 - 我得去撒泡大大的尿尿
Dude, any excuse for you to pull that thing out.
帅哥 你当众秀小弟弟真不害臊
Anyone got any beer?
有人带啤酒了吗？
We finished them all back at school. Besides, you've had enough.
我们在学校里都已经喝光了 何况 你也喝了不少
I've got one. It's not cold, but it's yours if you want it.
我有一瓶 不冰的 不过你要的话就拿去吧
All you gotta do is sit up, beg, roll over and shake that booty.
你现在要做的就是 好好利用你的那支赃物
- Thanks a lot, Eric. - Anytime, anywhere.
- 谢谢你的"建议" 埃里克 - 不客气 随时随地为你效劳
- This is gonna be sweet. - I'm glad I thought of it.
- 等会一定很过瘾 - 这个点子可是我想出来的哟
You're animals. Just because he's new.
你们真是禽兽 谁叫他是新生呢
You've talked shit the whole time. Why don't you be quiet?
你怎么总是废话连天 就不能安静一点吗？
You know how it is. Nobody's forcing him to show up.
你应该知道 根本就没有人强迫他来的
What if he doesn't? I want to go back to the dance.
如果他不来呢？我就要回去跳舞
Belinda, why don't you go back to the dance by yourself?
贝琳达 你为什么就不能一个人回去呢？
I wasn't talking to you, Dean.
我不是在跟你说话 迪恩
You know I don't dance.
你知道我不跳舞的
It's true. I've seen him bust a move. It ain't pretty.
这是事实 我曾经看过他跳舞 简直难看死了
But a brother like me is ready to get his freak on. What you say?
不过象我这样的帅哥 倒是愿意奉陪一下 你觉得呢？
Put it away before you hurt somebody.
在你踩伤别人之前就快点滚开
Like yourself.
正如你一样
He's here!
他来了！
All right, here he comes.
好啦 终于来了
Hey, check out the Safari Joe truck.
嘿 看看这辆傻瓜旅行车
I can't wait to see you fly!
我已经等不及要看你"飞"了！
Hey, nice shirt, Opie.
嘿 衬衫不错嘛 小菜鸟
You're late.
你迟到了
I thought I said be here at 10, but you know..
我想我说过了要准时10点到这里 不过你知道
When I say be here at 10, be here. Can you remember that next time?
我说10点到 你就得准时到 下一次能记住吗？
If there is a next time!
如果还有下一次的话！
Dean! Is he always like that?
迪恩！他经常是那样的吗？
Always, man. So how about it? You ready to fly?
一直都是 兄弟 怎么样？准备好去"飞"了吗？
Wait up, baby!
等一等 宝贝！
Let me get on your back. Giddyap! Giddyap!
让我骑在你的背上 跑啊！跑！
Okay, here's the deal.
好吧 来单交易吧
You're gonna jump from up there into here.
你从那上面跳到这个水池里
That's it, and you're one of us. Okay?
就这么简单 然后你就可以加入我们了 这么样？
- You ready? - Yeah.
- 准备好了吗？- 没问题
All right. All right.
好吧 好吧
Let's do this, okay?
那就开始吧 好吗
It's cake, man. Hell, I'm jumping with you.
小菜一碟 伙计 怕什么 我跟你一起跳
- How deep is this? - I don't really know.
- 这里有多深？- 不大清楚
Let's go find out.
那就让我们去看看 到底有多深
Let's do it.
来吧
Yeah! Shit, yeah!
去吧！该死的 跳吧！
Come on, let's go!
来 跳吧！
Jump!
跳吧！
- You done this? - We've all done it.
- 你以前也跳过吗？- 这里每个人都跳过
- I hope you had your Wheaties! - You guys gonna do this tonight?
- 不要太胆小了！- 你们今晚到底还跳不跳？
On three.
数到3就跳
One.
一
Two.
二
Three!
三！
Oh, shit.
哦 见鬼
Landon, he's hurt!
兰登 他受伤了！
- Is he okay? - Landon, get down here!
- 他没事吧？- 兰登 快下来！
- What the hell? - Dean, what the hell?
- 搞什么鬼？- 迪恩 到底怎么啦？
- You guys, he's hurt! - Come on, man!
- 兄弟们 他受伤了！- 快来呀 你们！
- I told you it was a bad idea! - Get him out of the water!
- 我早就告诉过你们会出事的啦！- 快把他拖上岸！
- Hurry up! - Is he dead? What are we gonna do?
- 快点！- 他死了吗？我们现在怎办呀？
Help me!
帮帮我！
- Get him over here! - There's a pipe. He must have hit it!
- 快把他拉过来！- 有根管子 他一定是撞到管子了！
Get him out of the water!
快把他拖上岸！
Watch his head! Watch his head!
小心他的头！小心他的头！
Hey, who's down there?
嘿 谁在那儿吵？
Tracie, come on!
翠茜 快走！
Central, we've got trespassers. Send a squad car.
报警中心 这边有事发生 派一辆巡逻车过来
Come on, Landon.
快点 兰登
Come on!
快点！
You guys, just take him!
伙计们 快抓住他！
Give me his arms!
把他的胳膊给我！
I got him.
我拉住他了
We gotta get out of here.
我们得马上离开这里
- Go! Get out of here! - Landon, come on!
- 走！快走！- 兰登 快点！
I told you not to do this!
我早就叫你别这样！
Calm down.
冷静一点
Belinda, let's go!
贝琳达 走吧！
Come on, get in! I'm driving.
快点 上车！我已经启动了
Damn it!
该死的！
Shit!
见鬼！
Put your hands on the wheel.
把你的手放到方向盘上
You know, Mama, my leg really hurts today.
你知道吗 妈妈 今天我的腿真的很疼
I don't think I can go anyplace.
我想我哪里也去不了了
- Maybe I should call your father. - No.
- 也许我该给你父亲打个电话 - 不要
I'm not talking to him.
我不会跟他说话的
This has gotta stop between you two. You can't do that. You need a father.
你们之间的冷战必须停止了 你不能那样 你需要一个父亲
Let us be thankful today that a life was saved by our Lord.
今天让我们一起感谢主 因为主又挽救了一个年轻生命
And let us pray for the lives of the others involved..
同时也让我们 为与相关的人祈祷
who are clearly not on the path of righteousness.
这些明显已经走上歧途的人
- So how's the leg, man? - It's good.
- 你的腿怎么样了 伙计？- 好多了
I can't believe you were in jail.
我真不敢相信你不用坐牢
- What'd you tell them? - It was a nice night for a drive.
- 录口供时你说了些什么？- 我说那晚天气很好 我就开车出来兜风
Ended up at the cement factory, found Gephardt.
在水泥厂那边停了下来 发现了格普哈特
Tried to help him, got spooked.
过去想帮他 结果被吓了一跳
Figured I'd leave before they thought I was involved.
我怕被牵连 所以就赶快走
Gotta hand it to you. You're a Jedi Master of bullshit.
真要跟你击个掌 你是最会说瞎话的绝地武士
Damn, that Jamie Sullivan sure has style.
该死 那个婕米·沙利文穿衣服确实有"品味"
Wore that dress in the fourth grade.
都四年级了还穿这种裙子
It's the quiet ones you gotta watch.
就是要小心这种淑女
She might put it on a brother like a Pop-Tart.
说不定发起疯来 就把那衣服逢人就套
A little maintenance, she might not look bad.
只要稍微打扮一下 她会很漂亮的
Nice sweater.
毛衣很漂亮哦
Thank you.
谢谢
A student claims you were drinking on school property.
有个学生说 你当晚在学校喝了酒
Lucky for you, Clay Gephardt isn't talking.
你很走运 克莱·格普哈特没有说什么
The factory owners aren't pressing charges. At least not today.
工厂那边也没有追究赔偿 至少今天还没有
I said I'd arrange appropriate punishment.
我说过 我会给你一些适当的处罚的
What, are you gonna expel me?
怎么 你是不是准备要开除我？
Not yet.
还用不着
Besides attending class, you will help our janitorial staff after school.
除了正常上课以外 下课后你得帮学校的工人做义工
- For pay? - For the inner satisfaction it brings.
- 有报酬吗？- 这只是对你所犯错误的补偿
Saturdays, you'll tutor students at our sister school.
每个星期六 你还要为附中的学生辅导功课
You'll take part in the drama club's final event.
你还要参加学校的戏剧小组 和他们一起参加决赛
The spring play?
就是那个春季汇演？
It's time you experienced other things.
你应该要干点别的事情了
Started spending time with other kinds of people.
你该换些人交往了
Don't blow it, Landon.
不要再搞砸了 兰登
This is a device made of plastic wrap, a coat hanger and Wite-Out.
这个小发明 是由塑料包 衣架等组成
- Does anyone know what it is? - It's a star frame.
- 有人知道这是什么吗？- 是一个星星框
This is a star frame.
这是一个星星框
It will help you locate stars with your naked eye.
在你看星星的时候 能帮助你固定星星的位置
Mercury and Jupiter can be seen just over the west horizon after sunset.
日落后 在西边的地平线上 你能看到水星和木星
Bet you can see angels up there, flying around.
我打赌 你还能看到一群天使在飞来飞去
There are things that could be called miraculous.
在这个世界上 有样东西叫做奇迹
The more Einstein studied the universe, the more he believed in a higher power.
爱因斯坦对宇宙研究得越多 他就越相信有更强的力量存在
Well, if there is a higher power..
好吧 如果这个世界上真的有超自然力量的话
why can't he get you a new sweater?
那为什么他不给你弄条新裙子呢？
He's too busy looking for your brain.
他正忙于帮你找脑子呢
Laugh, it's a joke.
算了 笑话而已
- Let's get out of here. - I gotta stay.
- 我们走吧 - 我还要留在这
Principal's gone. Let's make some moves.
校长已经走啦 我们走吧
Come on. Come on.
来吧 走吧
I don't know. The custodian thing kind of suits you.
我不知道 你监护人的这套方法还真适合你
Thanks, buddy. Thank you.
谢了 兄弟 谢谢
Look at the chart, you'll see Halley's comet.
看看这张图 你们可以看到哈雷彗星
Okay, so I'll see you at school.
好吧 你到了 再见
My parents aren't home, if you want to come inside.
我父母不在家 你要进来吗？
Come on, Belinda. Nothing's changed.
别这样 贝琳达 一切都没有改变
I know. I just thought..
我知道 我只是在想
It's over.
我们完了
Yeah. Whatever.
嗯 管他呢
Okay.
好吧
Good morning, Landon.
早上好 兰登
Landon, wake up!
兰登 醒醒！
Come on. Up, up, up, up!
快点 起来 起来 起来 起来呀！
Up!
起床！
It's Saturday, no school.
今天是星期六 不用上学
Tutoring.
去辅导
Let's try this again.
我们再试一次
Which of these are similar triangles? This one or that one?
哪些是相同的三角形？这个还是那个？
What do you think?
你觉得是那个呢？
Man, I think this is bullshit!
大哥 我觉得简直是垃圾！
Makes two of us.
我也是这么觉得
Do you wanna buy some raffle tickets?
你想买一些抽奖券吗？
I'm trying to raise money to buy Jefferson new computers.
我正在努力筹钱 帮杰弗逊买一台新电脑
No.
不想
So I saw you in there with Luis.
我看到你辅导那个路易斯了
And I know it can be difficult..
我知道 刚开始可能比较艰难
but maybe you should back into it from somewhere else.
但也许下次 你可以换个切入点
Are you gonna go visit Clay Gephardt?
你想去看望克莱·格普哈特吗？
That would be a no.
那就是不去了
They moved him from the hospital to a rehab place on a street.
他们已经把他从医院转到社区康复医院了
Is this your idea of small talk something?
你这算是在搭讪吗？
If so, your social skills need work. No one force him jump.
如果是的话 你的社交能力有待提高 再说也没人逼他跳的
- It's called peer pressure. - How do you know that?
- 这叫"同辈压力" - 你怎么知道的？
You read it in your precious book?
就从你的那本宝贝书里学的？
Please don't pretend like you know me, okay?
拜托 你不要假装了解我了 好吗？
But I do. I do.
但我的确了解你 的确是
We have all the same classes since kindergarten.
从幼儿园开始 我们就一直同班
Why, you're Jamie Sullivan. You sit at lunch table seven.
你叫婕米·沙利文 你永远都在7号桌吃饭
It's not the reject table, but it's definitely self-exile territory.
那张桌子不算弃物 但已被我们定义为你的自我放逐之地
You have exactly one sweater. You look at your feet when you walk.
你永远只穿这件毛衣 你走路的时候总是看着你的脚
And for fun, you tutor on weekends..
更有趣的是 你还在周末辅导别人功课
and hang out with the Stars and Planets kids.
还和一帮"恒星" "行星"小孩一起玩
How's that sound?
怎么样？
Fairly predictable. Nothing I haven't heard before.
我早就想到你会这么说了 我什么话没听过呢
- You don't care what people think? - No.
- 那你不介意别人怎样说你的吗？- 不介意
I don't know what your problem is. Miss Garber has nice hooters.
我真不知道你是怎么了 加伯小姐胸够大
This is bullshit. Thanks.
别胡说了 谢了
I can't wait to see you in stage makeup. That's gonna be cool.
我好想看你在舞台上的样子 一定很酷
- Be back in an hour, okay? - Tell them maybe to do West Side Story.
- 1个小时后回来 好吗？- 能否让他们去演那个什么"西区故事"
Get that nice big-booty girl from Selena. Maria! Maria!
包括那个从塞琳娜来的大胸美女 玛丽亚！玛丽亚！
This year's spring musical is a story, burning passion and blazing Tommy guns.
今年音乐剧的主题是 燃烧的激情和炽热的冲锋枪
Written by our own Eddie Zimmerhoff. Words and music by Jamie Sullivan.
剧本由我们的艾迪·齐默霍夫撰写 台词和音乐由婕米·沙利文编写
It tells the story of Tommy "The Gun" Thornton in Prohibition - era New York.
它讲述一个纽约禁酒时期 名叫汤米·桑顿的人
Eddie, perhaps..
艾迪 大概
Mr.Carter, better late than never. Please join us.
卡特先生 迟到总比没到好 请坐吧
Sure.
好的
Now then, let's see..
现在 让我们来看看
Jamie will be our Alicia, a mysterious club singer.
婕米将扮演艾丽西娅 一个神秘的夜总会歌手
- Sally will be playing Caroline. - Congratulations.
- 莎莉将扮演卡罗琳 - 恭喜你
And Landon will read Tommy Thornton.
还有兰登将扮演主角 汤米·桑顿
No. No. See, I didn't plan on acting or anything.
不 不 瞧 我没打算要演个角色
When did you know, Tommy?
你什么时候知道的 汤米？
I Know what?
我知道什么？
That we were in love.
我们相爱了
Love?
爱？
Baby, you don't want to fall in love with a guy like me.
宝贝 你可别爱上一个像我这样的人
It's too late. I'm crazy about you.
太晚了 我已经疯狂地爱上了你
I'm breathing it, drinking it all in. Aren't you?
我呼吸的时候 喝水的时候 都感到爱的存在 你呢？
I don't know what I'm drinking, dollface, but if this is love..
我不知道我喝的是什么 娃娃脸 但如果这真的是爱的话
pour me another glass.
那就请再给我来一杯吧
Are you trying to be bad at this?
你要捣乱 是吗？
No, just comes naturally.
不 这是我的自然流露
All right, everybody, let's go to the end.
好吧 各位 我们到此为止
Don't even pretend you won't be great.
别再说自己做得不好
- Okay. I'll see you tomorrow. - All right. See you.
- 好吧 明天见 - 好吧 再见
Bye.
再见
- So would it kill you to try? - Yep, and I'm too young to die.
- 难道试一下会死人吗？- 是的 我不想死得太早
You don't care about classes and graduation, but you like school..
你不在乎课程和毕业 但你喜欢学校
because you're popular and you'll never be on top again.
因为你很潮 而且你再也不是了
- That's thoroughly predictable. - Your act only works on an audience.
- 那是很有可能发生的 - 你的表演只能感染你自己
Feeling Christian?
你是相信基督教的？
Seat belt?
安全带？
- I forfeit. - Thank you.
- 我投降 - 谢谢
Forty-two.
第42条
What do you mean, forty-two?
什么意思 第42条？
Forty-two is be friend somebody I don't like.
第42条是 善待我不喜欢的人
It's a to-do list I have except for my life.
属于一张必须为别人做的事的清单
Like getting a new personality?
比如什么"塑造一个新性格"？
Join the Peace Corps, make a medical discovery.
参加和平组织 来一项医学发现
Ambitious.
野心不小
Be in two places at once, get a tattoo.
同时出现在两个地方 弄个纹身
What's number one?
第1条是什么？
I'd tell you, but then I'd have to kill you.
如果我告诉了你 我就必须得杀了你
I've come..
我来
to see if you're ready.
看一下你是否已经准备好
Take a good look, lady. The only thing I'm ready for is a dirt nap.
看好啦 小姐 我唯一准备好的事情就是午睡
Ready to look into your heart, Tom Thornton.
准备看看你在想什么 汤姆·桑顿
Your words have been heard, and not just by me.
你的这些话不止我听过 其他人也听过
When you walked into..
当你走入
Shit. When you walked into my club, that wasn't just a coincidence.
见鬼 当时你走入我的夜总会 而那并不是巧合
Nothing's coincidence, baby.
没有事情是巧合的 宝贝
You know you're the only one who can make me sing.
你知道 你是唯一一个人能让我唱歌的
Yeah, Miss Garber! You'll put Eric in all your plays!
好 加伯小姐！你会让埃里克投入这个剧本！
Eric, I'll put you in all my plays!
埃里克 我会让你全身心投入到这个剧本的！
Come on. Do you know I got three weeks to memorize all this stuff?
拜托 你知道吗 我只有3个星期来记台词了
Man, you couldn't pull this off in three months, man!
伙计 给你3个月也不行 伙计！
De Niro couldn't even make this shit word!
德尼罗也办不到这事！
I didn't write it, okay?
这又不是我写的 好吗？
But you're gonna make a jackass of yourself in front of everyone.
但你在兄弟们面前快颜面尽失了
Look, I don't have a choice, so would you help me out, please?
听着 我没得选 所以请你帮帮我 好吗？
You know, I'm just busting on you.
你知道 我只想"揍"你一顿
I'll be there opening night, front row. And you can count on it.
我到时肯定捧场 前排 相信我
With tomatoes.
带上西红柿
Thanks, man.
谢了 兄弟
Landon? Boys, can you help with these groceries?
兰登？小伙子们 你们能不能帮我搬搬这些食物？
- Yeah. - No problem.
- 好的 - 没问题
Jamie.
婕米
What do you want, Carter?
你想怎样 卡特？
I've known you for years. You've never been the first to say hello.
我认识你多年了 你是永远不会第一个打招呼的
I need help with my lines.
我需要你帮我练习台词
- Landon Carter's asking me for help? - Yeah.
- 兰登·卡特在请我帮忙？- 是的
Okay, I'll pray for you.
好吧 我会为你祈祷的
Jamie, look..
婕米 听着
You've obviously never asked anybody for help before, right?
你以前从没有求别人帮忙过 对吗？
A request like yours requires flattery and groveling.
一个要求式的邀请 恭维 低声下气
It can't be about you. It has to be for the common good.
总不能一切以你为中心 你真的肯为大家牺牲吗？
It is for the common good. Eddie Zimmerhoff deserves the best.
确实是为了大家 艾迪·齐默霍夫的作品应得的
- Please? - Okay. One condition, though.
- 求你了？- 好吧 不过有一个条件
What's that?
是什么？
You have to promise you won't fall in love with me.
你一定要保证你不会爱上我
- That's not a problem. - Okay. I'll see you today after school.
- 那不是问题 - 好的 那我们今天放学后见
Landon Carter is coming here?
兰登·卡特要来吗？
He's dangerous, careless, the worst kind of bully.
他是危险的 粗心的 并只会欺负弱小
Daddy, what about forgiveness?
爸爸 宽恕他好吗？
I thought we had discussed that I would decide..
我们不是已经讨论过 让我来决定
how I wanted to spend my time and my life.
怎样支配我的时间和生活
It's him I don't trust, not you.
我只是不相信他而已 不是你
You gonna keep me out here all afternoon?
你是准备让我整个下午站在门外吗？
Come on in.
进来吧
My script is in my room. So, I'll be right down. Make yourself at home.
剧本在我的房间里 我去拿下来 别客气 就像在家一样
Oh, yeah.
哦 好的
It's not likely.
那是不太可能的
That is one scary-looking..
还真吓人
- Jesus! - No, Jamie's father.
- 上帝！- 我不是上帝 是婕米的父亲
Hello, Mr.Carter. I understand you're the lead in the play.
你好 卡特先生 我知道你是校剧的主角
Congratulations.
恭喜你
Thanks for letting me come over and run lines.
我很感谢您 能让我来这里练台词
I didn't let you.
我没有让你来
It's a school night. Let's get one thing straight, Mr.Carter.
这是一个学习的晚上 我说的直一点吧 卡特先生
You think that, on Sundays, I don't see you from where I stand.
你别以为 每个星期天我会对你视而不见
But I see you.
我看得到你
I'll be in my office, just here.
我会在我的办公室里 就这里
Ready?
准备好了吗？
Yeah, let's go.
准备好了 来吧
- Landon! Where have you been? - Nowhere.
- 兰登！你最近去哪儿啦？- 没去哪儿
- Hey, come here. - What's up?
- 嘿 过来 - 什么事？
- Are we cool? - Yeah, sure.
- 我们之间没问题吧？- 是呀 当然
What the hell?
搞什么鬼？
- What are you doing here? - I should ask you the same.
- 你在这里干什么？- 我也要问你同样的问题
Do you normally walk alone in a cemetery at night?
你总是晚上一个人在墓地里走动吗？
Maybe.
也许
Where you going?
你去哪儿？
Come and see.
过来看
Okay. What is that?
好吧 那是什么？
This is my telescope. I built it when I was 12.
这是我的望远镜 我在12岁的时候自己做的
Take a look.
看一下吧
Saturn. Very cool.
土星 真美
Yeah. I'm planning on building a larger one so I can see the comet Hyakutake.
是啊 我正打算做个更大的 这样我就能看到百武彗星了
It comes this spring. But..nobody knows when it'll be back.
今年春天能看到 但没人知道什么时候会来
Nature's miracles. I get it.
大自然的奇迹 我明白了
- Get what? - That you're into all this stuff.
- 明白了什么？- 你沉迷这些东西
This stuff?
这些东西？
I have my beliefs. I have faith, but don't you?
我有我的信仰 信念 难道你没有？
No. There's too much bad shit in this world.
不是的 这个世界上有太多糟糕的事了
Without suffering, there's no compassion.
没有受难 就没有同情
Tell that to those who suffer.
去和那些受苦的人说吧
This is what I love about early spring. Where those legs been hiding?
这就是我喜欢早春的地方 总是若隐若现
- She's trashy. - Well, if it isn't the Virgin Mary.
- 她那个太糟了 - 好吧 假如这不是圣母玛利亚
Here comes your leading lady.
你的女主角来了
Hey, Carter. So I'll see you after school?
嘿 卡特 我们今天放学后见？
In your dreams.
你做梦吧
Hi. Where's your sweater?
嗨 你的毛衣呢？
Let's get out of here.
我们走吧
What's up, dude?
怎么了 花花公子？
Come on, Jamie. Open the door, please!
拜托 婕米 开门吧 求你了！
What do you want?
你想怎样？
- You're not in a good mood. - You don't miss a thing.
- 你心情不好 - 你什么都知道
Listen, I was hoping we could run lines together.
听着 我只是希望我们在一起练台词
Okay, but just not so anybody knows, right?
好吧 但别让别人知道 对吗？
I just figured we could surprise everyone with how good I get.
我只是想给大家一个惊喜 让他们看看我演得有多好
We could be secret friends.
我们可以做秘密的朋友
Exactly! It's like you're reading my mind.
就是这样！我的想法都让你看透了
Great. Maybe you could read mine?
太好了 你也许可以猜到我的想法？
Jamie, I can't just be your friend.
婕米 我不能成为你的朋友
Landon, I thought I saw something in you. Something good.
兰登 我以为已经看到了你好的一面
But I was very wrong.
但现在我知道 我错了
Damn it!
该死的！
Sorry. Sorry.
对不起 对不起
婕米·沙利文 红十字会 天文社 戏剧社 理想：见证一个奇迹
You know the answer?
你知道答案了吗？
Come on, man, I know you know.
来吧 兄弟 我知道你能做的
Okay. It's you, me and the basket.
好吧 你 我 还有这个篮筐
We form the three corners of a triangle.
我们组成了三角形的3个角
Take a step towards the basket.
朝篮筐走一步
Am I at the same angle to you and the basket as before?
我们形成的3个角的度数和以前一样吗？
- Yeah. - Are you?
- 是的 - 真的？
- Yeah. - So, what did we just make?
- 是的 - 那么 现在形成了什么？
- A similar triangle? - Yes. Okay, make me an isosceles.
- 一个相似三角形？- 对了 好吧 来个等边三角形
You got it, two sides the same.
你成功了 两边一致
Okay, enough of this. Let's play.
好吧 今天到此为止 我们开始玩吧
I came to say I'm sorry.
我是来道歉的
Well, you did. Feel better?
呃 是嘛 你好点了吗？
No. I feel like shit.
没有 糟糕极了
You know what? I actually thought I wanted to be your friend.
你知道吗？我当时是真想跟你做朋友的
And now I have no idea why. No idea.
现在我真的不知道原因了 不知道
I made that jump once.
我真的跳过一次
I thought I was a badass.
我觉得我简直是个坏蛋
I remember actually saying that I meant to belly flop.
我记得我跳的时候 姿势跟你一样
Did it hurt?
受伤了吗？
Like hell.
像下地狱一样
Good.
好啊
So I guess I'll see you at school then.
那么我们学校见
- Pour me a drink, Joey. - You promised me, Tommy.
- 给我倒一杯酒 乔伊 - 你答应过我的 汤米
No more of your no - goodnik schemes.
再也不参与他们那些阴谋了
You promised me we'd go to Paris.
你答应过和我一起去巴黎的
I won't sit on my keister and watch the fat cats get rich.
我不想袖手旁观 看着那个肥猫越来越有钱
Trust me. This is a sure thing.
相信我 真的
That's it! We are through!
就这样吧！我们之间完了！
Go ahead and run your booze, you big dope!
去吧 去喝酒吧 你这个烂酒鬼！
And I hope you drown in it!
我真希望酒把你淹死
So you must be the new girl he's hired.
你一定就是他新雇的那个妞儿了
The singer?
歌手？
You want some free advice about this one? Stay far away.
要给你一个免费的建议吗？离他远一点
He's nothing but trouble in cheap spats.
他只会惹事生非
Look, I ain't blaming you.
听着 我不是在责备你
I ain't asking for forgiveness, either.
我也不是在请求宽恕
I just did what I had to.
我只是在做 我不得不做的事
When you walked out of the rain and into my club..
当你因为避雨 走进我的夜总会
that wasn't just coincidence, was it?
那不是巧合 对吗？
Nothing's coincidence.
没有事情是巧合的
Your face... You look so familiar.
你的脸 你看上去很亲切
Like this dame I knew once, only it wasn't real, it was a dream.
很像我以前认识的一位女士 只不过那不是真的 那是在梦里
Tell me about this dream girl.
和我聊聊 你的那位梦中女孩
Well, I don't remember.
呃 我记不起来了
All I know..
我只知道
is you're beautiful.
你很美
The song, the song.
歌 歌
The dream.
这个梦
Help me to remember.
帮我重拾回忆
Will you sing for me?
你会为我唱一首歌吗？
∮There's a song that's inside of my soul.∮
我灵魂深处有一首歌
∮It's the one that I've tried to write over and over again.∮
我一再尝试 把它谱成曲
∮I'm awake in the infinite cold.∮
早上醒来 是寒冷的苦楚
∮Would you sing to me? Over and over and over again?∮
你是否能为我再三而歌
∮So I lay my head back down.∮
我虔诚地低下头
∮And I lift my hands and pray.∮
我双手合十祈祷愿望
∮To be only yours. I pray to be only yours.∮
为你而生 我祈愿为你而生
∮I know now you're my only hope.∮
我终于明白 你是我唯一的希翼
∮Sing to me the song of the stars.∮
为我歌出一片星辰
∮Of your galaxy dancing and laughing and laughing again.∮
歌出你那舞跃欢笑的星宿
∮When it feels like my dreams are so far.∮
当我感到梦想如此遥远
∮Sing to me all the plans that you have for me over again.∮
请为我歌出一片天 我们在那再三地流连
∮So I lay my head back down.∮
我虔诚地低下头
∮And I lift my hands and pray.∮
我双手合十祈祷愿望
∮To be only yours. I pray to be only yours.∮
为你而生 我祈祷为你而生
∮I know now you're my only hope.∮
我终于明白你是我唯一的希翼
∮I gave my destiny.∮
我将命运交给你
∮I'll give you all of me.∮
我将一切交付与你
∮I want your symphony. Singing in all that I am.∮
由我体中迸发 直上云霄
∮At the top of my lungs. I'm giving it love.∮
直上云霄 我将给你全部的爱
∮So I lay my head back down.∮
我虔诚地低下头
∮And I lift my hands and pray.∮
我双手合十祈祷愿望
∮To be only yours. I pray to be only yours.∮
为你而生 我祈愿为你而生
∮I pray to be only yours.∮
我祈愿为你而生
∮I know now you're my only hope.∮
我终于明白你是我唯一的希翼
That was great.
太棒了
Hi, kids.
嗨 孩子们
Honey, I couldn't believe it. What a transformation.
亲爱的 我真不敢相信 你的变化太惊人了
Thanks, but please stop.
谢谢 请别这样
- Don't be home too late. - Okay. Thanks.
- 不要太晚回家 - 好的 谢谢
Okay, okay.
好的 好的
- Interesting rewrite you did there. - I did my best.
- 你临场发挥的那段很有意思 - 我想尽力
Your acting didn't suck either.
而且你的演技挺棒
- Gotta go. Take it easy, man. - Okay.
- 走了 可以放松点了 兄弟 - 好的
- Landon, you were marvelous! - Thank you.
- 兰登 你真了不起！- 谢谢
Landon? Fine performance, son.
兰登？出色的表演 儿子
- What are you doing here? - I thought we'd get a bite.
- 你来这里干什么？- 我们去吃顿饭吧？
- I'm not hungry. - Don't walk away.
- 我不饿 - 不要走
You taught me how.
这是你教我的
Oh, my God.
哦 我的天
Look who's here.
看谁来了
Don't look at him.
不要看他
You don't want to stare too much.
别一直死盯着他看
I guess he doesn't want to sit with us.
我猜他不会 跟我们一起坐了
- People can see. - That would ruin your reputation how?
- 别人会看见的 - 那会有损你的名声吗？
What's that?
那是什么？
《杀死一只知更鸟》
I'm reading books on Rothman's list of contemporary American authors.
我在看罗斯曼列出的 当代美国作家系列作品
- And how many books are there? - A hundred.
- 一共有多少本啊？- 100多本吧
But then there's his British list and his European list.
他还列了英国系列和欧洲系列的书目
So is this on your list, to read all these books?
那"看这些书" 在你的那个清单上面吗？
Jamie, I'm trying here, okay?
婕米 我在努力 怎么样？
Maybe..
也许
Maybe I miss spending time with you.
也许我想念跟你一起的时光
- Maybe you inspire me. - Sounds like bull.
- 也许你鼓舞和启发了我 - 听起来像空话
- Which part? - All of it.
- 那一部分？- 全部
- It's not. - Prove it.
- 不是的 - 证明给我看
Jamie!
婕米！
- You've no idea how to be a friend. - I don't just want that.
- 你根本不知道怎样做个朋友 - 我不是只想做朋友
You don't know what you want.
你不知道自己要什么
Neither do you. You're scared someone wants you.
你也好不到哪去 你很害怕别人喜欢你
- Why would that scare me? - You couldn't hide behind books..
- 为什么我会害怕？- 你不能老躲在书后面
or your fricking telescope, or your faith.
也不能躲在望远镜或你的信念后面
No. You know the real reason why you're scared?
不要 你知道你真正害怕的原因吗？
It's because you want to be with me too.
因为你也想跟我在一起
We gonna get this party jumping!
我们一起跳舞吧！
Can you turn down Soul Train? Some of us are trying to work.
你能把灵魂列车关了吗？我想做事
You really know how to bust a robot's groove.
你还真懂得给个机器人上发条啊
It's all good because we'll get Club Landon and Club Eric jumping now.
有什么不好呢 我们都可以跳跳舞
What we got here?
现在怎么样？
Okay, okay, you're not feeling my hip-hop, but what the hell is this?
好的 好的 你不再喜欢我的街舞了 可这又是什么？
Jamie lent it to me.
婕米借我的
You're listening to her people's music.
你在听她那些人的音乐
- Her people? - Yeah..
- 她那些人？- 是呀
her Bible-hugging, crucifix-wearing..
她的 耶稣的拥抱 戴十字架
honk - if - you - love - Jesus people.
你爱上耶稣的人了
- She's not like that. - Well..
- 她不是那样的 - 好吧
you got Belinda thinking that little lip action...
你知道贝琳达怎么想你们 话剧上那次接吻吗
between you and Jamie was kind of real.
她觉得你们是来真的
What's with you? You don't have time for your real friends anymore.
你怎么啦？你好象没时间跟你真正的朋友在一起了
I don't know, buddy. I'm just over it.
我不知道 兄弟 我已是局外人了
I'm sick and tired of doing the same shit all the time.
我已经厌倦了过去一成不变的蠢事
This girl's changed you, and you don't even know it, man.
这个女孩改变了你 连你自己都不知道 兄弟
- Let me guess, Belinda say that too? - No.
- 让我猜猜 贝琳达也这样说？- 没有
I did.
我说的
You.
你
Me.
是我
What is it?
那是什么？
I got you something.
我有东西要送给你
Thank you.
谢谢你
Well, I'll see you at school.
好了 我们学校见吧
Okay.
好的
- Mr.Carter. - Later, Reverend.
- 卡特先生 - 再见 牧师
Jamie..
婕米
Boys like that..
像那样的男孩子
they have..
他们
They have expectations.
肯定有所企图的
The rules around here aren't going to change.
别想改变我们这里的规则
Fine.
好啦
You might not care what I say or think..
也许你不在乎我的话和看法
but you should care about God's opinion.
但你应该在乎上帝的意见
I think he wants me to be happy.
我觉得他 只是想让我开心而已
Dad, it's just a sweater.
爸爸 只不过是一件毛衣嘛
I'm going to make us some dinner, okay?
我去准备晚饭 好吗？
I talked to your dad today.
今天我跟你爸爸谈过
Said he saw you at the play for about 10 seconds.
他说那天 你只给了他10秒时间
Sending a check once a month doesn't exactly make him a father.
每月送一次支票给我们 不能让他成为一个真正的父亲
- Landon, there are a lot of reasons.. - He left us.
- 兰登 那有很多原因 - 他离开了我们
You need to forgive him too.
你需要原谅他
Jamie Sullivan! Oh, me, oh, my, look at Jamie Sullivan.
婕米·沙利文！哦 我 哦 天啊 看婕米·沙利文
She was looking all right in that play.
她在戏剧里的装扮不错哦
She doesn't look hot.
但不火辣
Yeah, I would have to say during the play, she looked hot.
是啊 我不得不说 她在戏里真的很火辣
I have the best idea.
我有一个绝妙的点子
Can you do something, like, move it?
你能不能这样 比如 剪切出来？
Maybe move it around a little something here.
沿着这里 这里还有一点
Take one.
拿一张
Let me stop it for a second. Check it out.
等一会 弄出来
Hey, look at this.
嘿 看看这个
Here.
这里
Take one. Look.
拿一张 看
- Jamie. Hi. - Hi.
- 婕米 嗨 - 嗨
Listen, I just want you to know, no hard feelings.
听着 我只是想告诉你 我们没感觉了
Landon and I are way over.
兰登和我早分手了
I really don't know what you're talking about.
我真不知道你在说什么
You'd be so beautiful..
你真的会很漂亮
if you knew how to do your makeup.
如果你知道怎么化妆
- Come on, eat lunch with me. - Okay.
- 走 我们一起吃午饭吧 - 好吧
- Want a Tic Tac? - No, thanks.
- 要一个嘀嗒糖吗？- 不用了 谢谢
Okay.
好吧
Wow.
哇喔
Is that you?
那是你吗？
Nice bod.
挺辣的
Look, this is about me, okay? This is not you.
听着 这都是因我而起 知道吗？这不是针对你
Stay here.
在这儿等着
Hey, man, no wonder you been keeping her locked up.
嘿 兄弟 难怪你一直把她藏着呢
I had no idea this was underneath all that.
我以前真的不知道 好看的在里面
- Dean, stop! - You stay out of this!
- 迪恩 不要！- 你不要插手！
- We're through. We're through. - That's great.
- 我要跟你翻脸 我们翻脸了 - 那太好了
- We're through forever! - You okay?
- 我们永远翻脸！- 你怎么样？
- You made a mistake, Landon! - You sure?
- 你做了件错事儿 兰登！- 你肯定吗？
Let's get out of here.
我们走吧
Hey! You're a little chickenshit!
嘿！你只是不值一提的小混混！
Baby, I'm sorry. Okay?
宝贝 真对不起 好吗？
They're animals, all right?
他们的确是帮禽兽 对吗？
You want me to take you home?
要我送你回家吗？
Let's get out of here.
我们走吧
- Are you sure you're okay? - I'm fine.
- 你真的没事吗？- 我没事
- Thank you for everything. - You're welcome.
- 谢谢你 - 不客气
- I want to ask you something. - Okay.
- 我有件事求你 - 说吧
Will you go out with me on Saturday night?
这个星期六晚上 你愿意一起跟我出去吗？
I'm sorry. I can't go.
对不起 我不能
- You have something else going on? - No.
- 你是不是有其他事情？- 没有
- It's not that. - Then what is it?
- 不是那样的 - 那是什么？
I'm not allowed to date.
我爸爸不准我约会
"Do not be deceived. God is not mocked.
别被蒙骗 上帝是骗不了的
Whatever a man sows, that he will also reap.
只要有奉献 就会有回报
For he who sows to his flesh, will of the flesh reap.."
只要献出肉体 就能获得救赎
- Can I help you? - Yes, sir.
- 有什么事吗？- 是的 牧师
I'd like to ask your daughter to dinner on Saturday night.
我想邀请您的女儿 周六共进晚餐
That's not possible.
绝对不可能
With all due respect, sir, I ask you to reconsider.
恕我冒昧 牧师 我请求你再考虑一下
With all due respect, Mr.Carter, I made my decision.
恕我冒昧 卡特先生 我已经决定了
You can exit the way you entered.
你可以从你进来的地方出去
I'm sorry I haven't treated Jamie the way I should have.
我很抱歉 我没有好好地对待婕米
She deserves more than that.
她应该得到更多
I'm asking you for the same thing...
我只是请求你 答应我一件
you teach us every day in church.
你每天都教我们的事
And that's faith.
那就是信任
I can't believe you asked permission.
我不敢相信 你会去请求许可
It's no big deal. He was cool about it, anyway.
没什么大不了的 无论怎样 他还是很通情达理的
- Thank you. - This is for you.
- 谢谢你 - 这个是给你的
- Thank you very much. - Would you like something to drink?
- 非常感谢你 - 你要喝点什么吗？
- Sweet tea, please. - Make that two.
- 请给我一杯甜茶吧 - 那就两杯吧
Right away.
马上到
This place is really nice. Is this okay?
这个地方这么高档 没问题吧？
- Don't even worry about it, okay? - Okay.
- 不用担心 好吗？- 好的
Choose whatever you want.
喜欢什么就点什么
So, what'll it be?
那么 要点什么呢？
Is everything okay?
我可以收拾了吗？
- Thank you very much. - Yeah, me too. Thanks.
- 谢谢你 - 嗯 我也好了 谢谢
Would you like to dance?
要跳个舞吗？
Sorry, I don't dance.
抱歉 我不跳舞的
Me neither. I mean, not usually in front of anybody.
我也是 我的意思是 一般不在人前跳舞
Well, no. I mean, I don't at all. As in, I can't.
不行 我的意思是 我不跳 是因为 我根本不会
Everybody can dance.
每个人都会跳
Come on, you can't be that bad.
来吧 你不可能那么差劲的
Please?
拜托？
For me?
就当为了我 好吗？
Come on.
来吧
Sorry, I told you I was bad at this.
对不起 我说过我不行
- In all fairness, you warned me, right? - That's right.
- 很公道 你早提醒我了 对吗？- 算吧
So, what's number one on your list?
你任务清单里的第1条是什么？
Okay.
好吧
Number one on my list is getting out of Beaufort.
在我的清单里 第1条是离开波弗特
Getting out won't be your problem.
对你来说 那不成问题
It's more like figuring out what to do when you get somewhere.
更重要的是到了一个地方后 你准备做什么
What do you mean?
什么意思？
I mean, you can do anything.
我的意思是 你可以做任何事
- Where are we going? - Just hold on, you'll see.
- 我们现在去哪儿？- 别急 你会知道的
Come on, come on. Let's go!
来吧 来吧 走！
- What are we doing? - Run!
- 我们要干什么？- 跑！
- Okay, okay. Stand there. - All right.
- 好的 好的 站在那 - 好的
- One foot there, and one foot here. - Okay.
- 一只脚在那边 一只脚在这边 - 好的
You're acting crazy. What's going on?
你疯了 搞什么鬼嘛？
Right now, you're straddling the state line.
现在 你跨越了两州的边界
Okay.
好的
You're in two places at once.
你现在同时出现在两个地方
Okay, butterfly, rosebud or star?
好吧 蝴蝶 蔷薇花 还是星星？
You choose.
你选吧
- Butterfly. - Okay.
- 蝴蝶 - 好的
Where do you want it?
要纹在哪里？
Right here.
就这里吧
Okay.
好的
How can you see places like this..
你怎么能看到这些
and have moments like this, and not believe?
怎能拥有这样的时刻 却不敢相信？
You're lucky to be so sure.
你能如此坚信
It's like the wind.
就像风
I can't see it, but I feel it.
我看不到 但我能感觉到
What do you feel?
你感觉到什么？
I feel wonder and beauty..
我感觉到奇妙 美好
joy, love.
喜悦 爱
I mean, it's the center of everything.
我的意思是 就像世界的中心
I might kiss you.
我可以吻你吗
I might be bad at it.
我可能技术很烂
That's not possible.
不可能
I love you.
我爱你
Now would be the time to say something.
现在该你说点什么了
I told you not to fall in love with me.
我告诉过你 叫你别爱上我
Jamie. Say good night to Mr.Carter.
婕米 跟卡特先生说再见
Landon, go home. The night's over.
兰登 回家吧 今晚到此为止
- Good night. - Good night.
- 晚安 - 晚安
Good night, sir.
晚安 先生
Jamie, your behavior's sinful.
婕米 你的行为是有罪的
- You act with that boy like you're.. - In love?
- 你和那男孩的行为就像是 - 恋爱了？
- Jamie, you are a child. - Dad, look at me..
- 婕米 你还是个孩子 - 爸爸 看着我
- ..I'm not a child. - Then stop acting childish.
- 我不是孩子了 - 那就别再幼稚了
I love him.
我爱他
Then be fair to him, Jamie, before things get worse.
那就对他公平点 婕米 在事情变得更糟之前
- Will you help me? - Yeah.
- 帮帮我好吗？- 好
So, what did you tell your father?
那么 你告诉你父亲什么了？
The truth. I just left you out of it.
实际上 我说我会让你出局
So, what do you want to see?
那么 你想要看什么？
Pluto.
冥王星
Pluto only rises a few minutes before the sun.
冥王星只会在太阳出来前几分钟出现
Right..
好
and I have brought us a thermos of hot coffee..
我已经带好了一瓶热咖啡
and a blanket.
还有一条毯子
- You planned this. - Oh, I hoped for it.
- 你计划好的 - 哦 我也希望是这样
Are you trying to seduce me?
你是在试图引诱我吗？
Why? Are you seducible?
怎么？你会上当吗？
That's what I thought..
我也这么认为
ergo, a second blanket.
因此 还有第二条毯子
- One for me, and one for you. - Thank you.
- 一条给我 一条给你 - 谢谢
- Can you find this star right here? - Sure.
- 你能找到图上这颗星吗？- 当然
So why am I looking for this star?
为什么要找这颗星啊？
Because I had it named for you.
因为我用你的名字命名了它
See?
瞧？
It's official.
是官方的
It's from the International Star Registry.
是来自于国际星体注册机构
This is wonderful!
太好了！
I love you.
我爱你
Okay, okay. I'm sorry. I'm stopping.
好了 好了 很抱歉 我们要停一下
So, what's your number one?
那么 你的第1条任务是什么？
To marry in the church where my mother grew up.
在我母亲长大的教堂里结婚
That's where my parents were married.
那也是我父母结婚的地方
- Did you just get in? - Yeah.
- 你刚刚回来？- 是的
Thank heavens I didn't know. I'd have been panicked.
感谢上帝 我不知道 我会害怕的
Sorry.
对不起
Landon, were you with Jamie?
兰登 你是跟婕米一起吗？
Landon, be careful. She's the reverend's daughter.
兰登 认真点 她是牧师的女儿
- Mom.. - Please!
- 妈妈 - 求你了！
It's different with her.
跟她这次 不同以往
- It's different with her. - Yes.
- 不同 - 是的
It better be different with her.
最好是有所不同
I was doing laundry the other day, and I found this.
我在洗衣服的时候 发现了这个
"Examine a moon rock.
检测月球岩石
Go to college.
上大学
Get into medical school."
要上医学院
Honey, these are really beautiful ambitions.
亲爱的 这是很美好的雄心
- But you'll have to work really hard. - I can do that.
- 但你真的得非常努力才行 - 我能做到的
Yeah, you can.
当然 你可以
Mama..
妈妈
Jamie has faith in me.
婕米 她相信我
You know?
你知道吗？
She makes me want to be different.
她令我想做出改变
Better.
变得更好
I was so drunk, I don't remember anything.
我喝醉了 我记不起任何事情
That's great. Citizen high to citizen low.
那太好了 由高等公民到低等公民
Are you worried about your college applications?
你是在担心你的大学申请吗？
No.
不是
I'm not applying.
我没有申请
- I thought you said.. - No, you assumed.
- 我以为你会说 - 不 只是你的假定
- Take a year off, try the Peace Corps? - No.
- 花一年时间参加和平组织？- 不
What are you gonna do?
那你打算干什么？
I'm sick.
我病了
- I'll take you home, you'll be.. - No, Landon!
- 我送你回家吧 你会 - 不 兰登！
I'm sick.
我病了
I have leukemia.
我有白血病
No.
不
- You're 18, you're perfect. - No.
- 你才18岁 你是完美的 - 不
I found out two years ago. I've stopped responding to treatments.
两年前就发现了 现在所有治疗都对我无效了
So why didn't you tell me?
那为什么不告诉我？
The doctor said I should live life normally, as best I could.
医生说 我应该竭力像正常人一样生活
I didn't want anybody to be weird around me.
我不想让其他人觉得我很怪异
- Including me? - Especially you!
- 包括我吗？- 特别是你！
I was getting along fine. I accepted it, and then you happened!
我一直一个人过的好好的 我也认了 而你出现了！
I do not need a reason to be angry with God.
我不想有怨恨上帝的理由
Dad, open the door!
爸爸 开门！
Landon?
兰登？
- I need your help. - What's wrong? You okay?
- 我需要你的帮忙 - 怎么了？你没事吧？
It's my girlfriend, Jamie. She's..
我女朋友 婕米 她
She's got cancer. And I need you to come and see her right now.
她得了癌症 我需要你马上来看看她
Okay, calm down.
好的 先冷静下来
- Can you help me or not? - I don't know her case.
- 你能帮还是不能帮？- 我不了解他的病情
I don't know her history. I'm a cardiologist. I can't..
我不知道她的病史 我是一名心脏病医生 我无法
You know, just forget it. I knew it.
这样 那就算了 我早就知道
Would you wait? Landon, wait!
你等会儿行吗？兰登 等等！
Your mom called me.
你妈妈给我打过电话
Talk to me, man.
跟我谈谈 兄弟
About what?
谈什么？
About you..
关于你
about Jamie.
关于婕米
What's there to talk about?
从何谈起？
She's the best person I've ever known.
她是我遇到过的最好的人
I didn't understand.
我无法理解
It's okay, man.
没事了 兄弟
It's okay.
没事了
It's so nice to see you again. You're welcome. Watch yourself now.
能再见到你 我真高兴 不客气 慢走
I'm not going anywhere.
我不会离开她的
Please tell Jamie that.
请替我告诉婕米
I'm so sorry. I really should have told you sooner.
我很抱歉 我真应该早点告诉你
I made you do too many things..
我还让你跟着我 干了那么多事情
If anything, you kept me healthy longer.
如果真做了什么 也是让我活得更久
Are you scared?
你害怕吗？
To death.
怕死
Lighten up.
不要紧的
It's not funny.
别开玩笑了
I'm scared of not being with you.
我只怕不能跟你在一起
Oh, baby, that will never happen.
哦 宝贝 那永远不会发生
I'll be here.
我会一直在你身边
Mom.
妈妈
Can you do me a favor?
你能不能帮我一个忙？
So I talked to Eric.
我跟埃里克谈过了
Need some help with this stuff?
需要帮忙搬东西吗？
Sure.
当然
What's that boy doing in the yard?
那孩子在花园里干什么？
What's the matter? Jamie, honey?
怎么啦？婕米 宝贝？
Landon. Run along, son.
兰登 去休息一会儿 孩子
I'm not tired.
我不累
I need just a minute with her.
让我陪她一会儿
- I'll be back, okay? - Okay.
- 我很快回来 好吧？- 好的
Daddy..
爸爸
so serious.
这么严重吗
Do you remember when you were about 5 or 6..
你还记得吗 在你5-6岁的时候
and you said you hated gravity..
你说你不喜欢地心吸力
and you wanted to jump off the roof and fly?
你喊着要从屋顶跳下来 你要飞起来
I was so angry at you for making me come down.
我当时很生你的气 你没有达成我的心愿
Honey, if I kept you too close, it's because I wanted to keep you longer.
亲爱的 我只想把你留在身边 因为我想让你活得更长一点
Dad..
爸爸
You know, when I lost your mother..
你知道吗 当我失去了你母亲以后
I was afraid that my heart would never open again.
我真害怕我再也不能敞开心扉
Jamie, I couldn't look at you for days.
婕米 那些天我都没理过你
But then..
但
I love you so much.
我是如此的爱你
I wanted to give you these.
我来给你这个
The pictures from the play.
那部戏里的剧照
- I'm sorry about the flyers. - It doesn't matter.
- 上次的事很抱歉 - 算了
I guess you're with who you should be.
我猜你遇到了命中注定之人
It's like she chose you.
象是她选中了你
Yeah, I don't even know why.
是啊 我也不知道为什么
I do.
我知道
How you feeling?
你觉得怎样？
- I'm okay. How are you? - Pretty good.
- 很好 你呢？- 非常好啊
- I have something for you. - You do?
- 我有些东西要给你 - 是吗？
Don't worry, it's not a Bible.
不用担心 那不是圣经
It was my mother's. It's got quotes from her favorite books..
是我母亲的 都是从她最喜欢的书里摘录的
and quotes by famous people. Her thoughts.
还有名人名言 她的感想
- Come on. - Okay, let's check it out.
- 来 - 好的 让我们来看看
"What is a friend?
朋友是什么？
It's a single soul dwelling in two bodies. Aristotle."
是同时存在于两人体内的灵魂 亚里士多德"
- Right here. - Okay.
- 看这里 - 好的
"Find out who you are..
真正认清自己
and do it on purpose."
并朝着目标不断前进
That's Dolly Parton.
那是多莉·帕顿
I always thought she was smart.
我一直都认为她很聪明
"Love is always patient and kind. It is never jealous.
爱要有忍耐和仁慈 永远没有妒忌
Love is never boastful or conceited.
有爱就永远不要自负
It is never rude or selfish.
不要无礼和自私
It does not take offense and is not resentful."
不要侵犯和愤怒
- You know what I figured out today? - What?
- 你知道我今天想到了什么吗？- 什么？
Maybe God..
也许上帝
has a bigger plan for me than I had for myself.
有一个更大的任务给我
Like, this journey never ends.
就像 这个永远没有终点的旅程
Like, you were sent to me because I'm sick.
就像 因为我病了 你就被送给了我
To help me through all this.
帮我度过这一切
You're my angel.
你是我的天使
What's going on?
什么事？
I get to go home. Please thank your father for me.
我可以回家了 请谢谢你父亲为我做的一切
- What does she mean? - He's been trying to reach you.
- 什么意思？- 他一直在努力靠近你
He's going to pay for private home care.
他出钱为我们请了私人家庭护理
Thank you.
谢谢你
Sorry.
对不起
It's all right, son.
没事了 孩子
- I gotta finish this tonight. - Here, something hot.
- 我要今晚完成这个 - 来 喝杯热的
Almost finished. Did you order the mirrors?
快完成了 你帮我订镜片了吗？
- Yeah, they're in here. - Good.
- 有啊 都在这儿 - 好
- What about side bearings? - An old phonographic turntable.
- 侧面如何？- 用一个老式留声机的转盘就行了
So you think you can get all this done by tomorrow?
你认为可以在明天之前搞定吗？
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
- 谢谢你 - 不用客气
It's beautiful.
太漂亮了
Okay, it's time. Go check it out.
好了 时间到了 我们去看看
There it is.
就那里
Come here. Come look.
过来 过来看
Come here. Come look, quick.
快来 看一下 快点
That is cool.
太美了
Do you love me?
你爱我吗？
- Will you do something for me then? - Anything.
- 你能答应我一件事吗？- 任何事都可以
Will you marry me?
你愿意嫁给我吗？
"Love is always patient and kind. It is never jealous."
爱要有忍耐和仁慈 永远没有妒忌
- I love you. - "Love is never boastful nor conceited.
- 我爱你 - 有爱就永远不要自负
It is never rude or selfish.
不要无礼和自私
It does not take offense and is not resentful.
不要侵犯和愤怒
Love takes no pleasure in other people's sins..
爱使你不会因别人的过失而不愉快
but delights in the truth.
但会因为真相而喜悦
It is always ready to excuse, to trust, to hope..
要一直准备着去原谅 去信任 去希望
and to endure..
还有去忍耐
whatever comes."
无论发生什么
- I, Landon Rollins Carter.. - I, Jamie Elizabeth Sullivan..
- 我 兰登·罗林斯·卡特 - 我 婕米·伊丽莎白·沙利文
do solemnly swear..
庄严地宣誓
- ..to take Jamie Sullivan.. - ..to take Landon Rollins Carter..
- 娶婕米·伊丽莎白·沙利文 - 嫁兰登·罗林·卡特
- ..as my wife. - ..as my husband.
- 作为我的合法妻子 - 作为我的合法丈夫
To honor and to cherish her, all the days of my life.
尊敬并珍惜她 用我一生的时间
Jamie and I had a perfect summer together..
婕米和我 度过了一个完美的夏天
with more love than lots of people know in a lifetime.
我们的爱 超过了很多人一生所知
And then she went, with her unfailing faith.
最后她走了 带着她永恒的信念
It's been four years..
四年过去了
but the vision of Jamie walking towards me..
但"婕米"一直陪伴着我
will stay with me forever.
直到永远
Hello, Mr.Carter. Come in.
你好 卡特先生 进来
- Have a seat, please. - Thank you.
- 请坐吧 - 谢谢
Landon.
兰登
- You look good. - Thank you. You too.
- 你看上去不错 - 谢谢 你也是呀
I'm getting by.
我刚好路过
- What's new, Landon? - Well, I got into medical school.
- 有什么好事吗 兰登？- 我进了医学院
Your mother told me that.
你母亲告诉我了
We're so proud of you. Jamie would have been proud of you too.
我们为你感到骄傲 婕米也会为你感到骄傲
Listen.
听着
I want you to have this.
我希望您可以保管这个
Oh, Landon.
哦 兰登
Oh, my.
哦 天呐
Thank you.
谢谢你
I'm sorry she never got her miracle.
我很抱歉 没能让她看到奇迹
She did.
她看到了
It was you.
那就是你呀
Jamie saved my life.
婕米挽救了我
She taught me everything.
她教会了我一切
About life, hope..
关于生命 希望
and the long journey ahead.
还有前方的道路
I'll always miss her.
我会永远想她
But our love is like the wind.
但我们的爱 就像风
I can't see it..
看不到
but I can feel it.
但感觉得到